<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Automation - Category - Robert Guske</title>
        <link>https://rguske.github.io/categories/automation/</link>
        <description>Automation - Category - Robert Guske</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>robert.guske@gmail.com (Robert Guske)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>robert.guske@gmail.com (Robert Guske)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License. © All rights reserved -2018</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 21:30:31 &#43;0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rguske.github.io/categories/automation/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Elevate Your Cloud-Native Journey: Knative the VMware Tanzu Way Part I - Streamlined Installation of Knative</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/elevate-your-cloud-native-journey-knative-the-vmware-tanzu-way-part-1-streamlined-installation-of-knative/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 21:30:31 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/elevate-your-cloud-native-journey-knative-the-vmware-tanzu-way-part-1-streamlined-installation-of-knative/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/cnr_knative_cover.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Knative 💙 In the rapidly evolving landscape of modern software architecture, event-driven systems have emerged as a pivotal paradigm, empowering organizations to create highly responsive, scalable, and adaptable applications. Knative stands at the forefront of this revolution, offering a robust and flexible framework for building event-driven architectures (EDA) that seamlessly integrate diverse components, enhance automation, and enable real-time data processing.
I&rsquo;m evangelizing and supporting the Knative project for a longer time already.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>vSphere with Tanzu Supervisor Services Part IV - Virtual Machine Service to support Hybrid Application Architectures</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-with-tanzu-supervisor-services-part-iv-virtual-machine-service-to-support-hybrid-application-architectures/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 19:48:14 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-with-tanzu-supervisor-services-part-iv-virtual-machine-service-to-support-hybrid-application-architectures/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/ova-vm-service-cover.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Hybrid Application Architectures As technology advances at a rapid pace, the landscape of application development continues to evolve. The demand for agility, scalability, and cost-effectiveness has given rise to a new breed of architectures that seamlessly integrate modern cloud-native principles with established traditional workloads. One such paradigm that has gained significant traction is the hybrid application architecture, which combines the power of service-oriented architectures (SOA) with the reliability and versatility of virtual machines (VMs).]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Building a VMware PhotonOS based Kubernetes Appliance for vSphere</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/building-a-vmware-photonos-based-kubernetes-appliance/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 14:19:55 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/building-a-vmware-photonos-based-kubernetes-appliance/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/kubernetes_appliance_cover.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Why a Kubernetes-Appliance? Learning Kubernetes (K8s) is still in great demand and is by no means decreasing. Starting with the theory is essential but we all know, the fun part starts with pactice. Quickly instantiating a Kubernetes cluster is made easy and I&rsquo;m pretty sure it won&rsquo;t take long until KinD crosses your path. But sometimes, a local K8s instance isn&rsquo;t enough and practicing Kubernetes low-level implementations like e.g. for networking (CNI) or storage (CSI) on real cloud environments is crucial.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Deploying Tanzu Packages using Tanzu Mission Control Catalog</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/deploying-tanzu-packages-using-tanzu-mission-control-catalog/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 20:00:27 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/deploying-tanzu-packages-using-tanzu-mission-control-catalog/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/tmc_catalog_202201_cover.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>The Challenge Just providing a Kubernetes cluster to an application team is in most cases half of the battle. It&rsquo;s often necessary to provide certain capabilities for e.g. logging or for ingress to those clusters, to ultimately support a production workload. Extending Kubernetes environments with open source solutions, to support the aforementioned capabilities, should provide a decent level of simplicity in terms of deployment and lifecycle management.
A Catalog of Extensions Tanzu Mission Control, a VMware Cloud Service (SaaS), is VMware&rsquo;s multi-cloud Kubernetes management platform which provides a centralized management for consistently operating and securing Kubernetes infrastructures and modern applications through a centralized policy management across all deployed and attached Kubernetes clusters.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>VMware Event Broker Appliance - vSphere HA Event Notification Function</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-ha-event-notification-function/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 15:19:05 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-ha-event-notification-function/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/harestartfunction_cover.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>A post about a community function contribution to the open source project VMware Event Broker Appliance to notify you if a ESXi host failure occured.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>VMware Enterprise PKS Management Console (EPMC) - Day 1</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/pks-management-console-day-1/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 14:53:23 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/pks-management-console-day-1/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/epmc_day1_cover.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>The Enterprise PKS Management Console really improves the overall Day-1 and Day-2 experience by greatly simplifying the deployment process of Enterprise PKS (Day-1) and additionally providing a rich set of features around Visibility, User Management and Upgrades/Patches (Day-2).]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>VMware Enterprise PKS Management Console (EPMC) - Day 2</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/pks-management-console-day-2/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 14:40:23 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/pks-management-console-day-2/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/epmc_day2_cover.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>I covered the Day-1 capabilities of the new version of the Enterprise PKS Management Console (EPMC) in my previous post. Let´s have a look at what´s in for Day-2.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>docker run vic-machine</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/docker-run-vic-machine/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 22:52:18 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/docker-run-vic-machine/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/dockerrunvicmachine_cover.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>A guide through the various steps to consume vic-machine and every specific action of it in a simplified fashion AND have it running in a container pulled out of Harbor or from another repository of your choice.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
