<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PKS on </title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/tags/pks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PKS on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 14:53:23 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rguske.github.io/tags/pks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Enterprise PKS Management Console (EPMC) - Day 1</title>
      <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/pks-management-console-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 14:53:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/pks-management-console-day-1/</guid>
      <description>Version 1.5.0 of VMware´s turnkey solution VMware Enterprise PKS, which brings production-grade Kubernetes to enterprises, was released back in August this year. This release introduced the beta (v.0.9) of the VMware Enterprise PKS Management Console (EPMC) which offers an opinionated installation of Enterprise PKS. With the PKS minor release v.1.5.1, the EPMC went GA in version 1.0.0.
Further improvements and enhancements were made in version 1.6 (*1), which went GA on the 26th of November, a few days after the release of Enterprise PKS v.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Enterprise PKS Management Console (EPMC) - Day 2</title>
      <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/pks-management-console-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 14:40:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/pks-management-console-day-2/</guid>
      <description>In the previous blog post we went through the Day-1 capabilities of the new version of the Enterprise PKS Management Console (EPMC). Let´s have a look at what´s in for Day-2.
Summary Page The summary page of your Enterprise PKS deployment will appear after clicking the Enterprise PKS button at the top left corner. This page will give you an detailed overview of all the PKS Management Plane components including important data like, Service State, Version Numbers, IP addresses and also Hyperlinks either to the relevant Virtual Machine in vSphere or to the Website of an Management-Component like, NSX-T or the Pivotal Ops Manager.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>