<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Robert Guske</title>
        <link>https://rguske.github.io/</link>
        <description>rguske.github.io is a personal website which provides informational &amp; detailed content, based on Robert GuskeÂ´s gained experiences with solutions by VMware (primarily).</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>robert.guske@gmail.com (Robert Guske)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>robert.guske@gmail.com (Robert Guske)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License. Â© All rights reserved -2018</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 10:00:14 &#43;0100</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://rguske.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>vSphere with Tanzu - Troubleshooting HAProxy deployment</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-with-tanzu-troubleshooting-haproxy/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 10:00:14 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-with-tanzu-troubleshooting-haproxy/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/haproxytroubleshooting_cover.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Introduction You may have already heard and read about our latest changes regarding our Kubernetes offering(s) vSphere with Tanzu also former known as vSphere with Kubernetes. Personally, I was totally excited and full of anticipation to make my first hands-on experience with this new deployment option &ndash;&gt; vSphere Networking as an alternative to NSX-T and how HAProxy is doing it&rsquo;s job within this construct. I don&rsquo;t know how you are dealing with installations of the &ldquo;NEW&rdquo; but I always read the documentation first&hellip; &hellip; not &hellip; ðŸ™Š &hellip; but I should!]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>A practitioner&#39;s guide - Spin up a local VEBA environment with KinD and vCenter simulator</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/spin-up-a-local-veba-environment-with-kind-and-vcenter-simulator/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 12:00:57 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/spin-up-a-local-veba-environment-with-kind-and-vcenter-simulator/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/vebakindvcsim_cover.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Introduction In my previous blog post I took A closer look at VMware&rsquo;s Project Nautilus and went through some of the implementation details (Fusion 12). I described how it provides a single development platform on the desktop by enabling you to run, build and manage OCI compliant Containers as well as how easy it is now to instantiate Kubernetes Clusters besides Virtual Machines.
The question This post is intented to answer a question which came into my mind during my work on VMware&rsquo;s Open Source project VMware Event Broker Appliance (VEBA) and as I&rsquo;ve heard of Project Nautilus for the first time.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>A closer look at VMware&#39;s Project Nautilus</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/a-closer-look-at-vmwares-project-nautilus/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 11:45:57 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/a-closer-look-at-vmwares-project-nautilus/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/projectnautilus_cover.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>General Availability Fusion 12 &amp; Workstation 16 VMware&rsquo;s Desktop Hypervisor solutions Fusion for Mac users and Workstation for the Windows and Linux userbase were launched in it&rsquo;s newest versions on September 15th. Lots of new features, enhancements and support around VM Guest Operating Systems, VM Scaling, GPU, Containers and Kubernetes has made it into these releases. The made enhancements will enrich Developers tool kit as well as will provide great new capabilities for IT Admins and everyone else who is keen on spinning up and down Virtual Machines, Containers and NOW also Kubernetes.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>vSphere 7 with Kubernetes supercharged - Helm, Harbor and Tanzu Kubernetes Grid</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-7-with-kubernetes-supercharged-helm-harbor-tkg/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 15:30:38 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-7-with-kubernetes-supercharged-helm-harbor-tkg/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/harborontkg_cover.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>I recently had to prepare my homelab for a customer workshop to demo our new Tanzu Runtime &amp; Hybrid Infrastructure Services. This includes e.g. the deployment of a Tanzu Kubernetes Grid Cluster on vSphere (TKG Service), the enterprise cloud native registry Harbor as well as the instantiation of a native Pod on vSphere (vSphere Pod Service).
Figure I: Tanzu Runtime &amp; Hybrid Infrastructure Services" Figure I: Tanzu Runtime &amp; Hybrid Infrastructure Services  My demo was basically all about the deployment of an application running natively (Native Pod) on vSphere, whose container image I pushed beforehand into my Harbor registry and which in turn was then obtained from there during the application deployment.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>VMware Event Broker Appliance - vSphere HA Event Notification Function</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-ha-event-notification-function/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 15:19:05 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-ha-event-notification-function/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/harestartfunction_cover.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Community I recently had the pleasure to suppport a member out of the VMware Event Broker Appliance (VEBA) Slack Community with his function example contribution to the VEBA project. His name is Bob. He introduced his Powershell/ PowerCLI function on a remote session to me and I was immediately thrilled about what the function does. It covers a use case that one of my customers brought up some time ago when I first introduced VEBA to them.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Monitoring the VMware Event Broker Appliance with vRealize Operations Manager</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/monitoring-the-vmware-event-broker-appliance-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 23:59:50 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/monitoring-the-vmware-event-broker-appliance-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/vrops_veba_cover.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Since the VMware Event Broker Appliance (VEBA) is reaching more and more folks out there and the interest is growing steadily, it is important to validate the integration with other solutions (preferably VMware). At least that&rsquo;s what I thought ðŸ˜‰.
Monitoring in terms of utilization and performance captured my interest. So, how can I monitor not only the appliance (virtual machine) but also the Kubernetes components like the Control Plane (Master), the Node(s) as well as the Pods?]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>VMware Enterprise PKS got rebranded VMware Tanzu Kubernetes Grid Integrated Edition</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/tanzu-kubernetes-grid-integrated-edition-management-console-1-7/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 14:00:24 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/tanzu-kubernetes-grid-integrated-edition-management-console-1-7/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/tkgimc17_cover.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>&hellip;and thus also the Enterprise PKS Management Console (EPMC), which is now inferring named as Tanzu Kubernetes Grid Integrated Edition Management Console (TKGIMC).
Quote  &rdquo;&hellip;VMware is announcing important milestones for key products in the VMware Tanzu portfolio, which brings consistency to building, running, and managing code. VMware is the only company that addresses the challenges of application modernization from both the application and the infrastructure perspective.&quot;
Source: https://tanzu.vmware.com/content/blog/consistency-matters-tanzu-application-service-kubernetes
   Referring to this ðŸ‘†, this rebranding was necessary to unify VMware&rsquo;s Kubernetes offerings under the Tanzu umbrella.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Using Harbor with the VMware Event Broker Appliance</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/using-harbor-with-the-vcenter-event-broker-appliance/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 22:00:36 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/using-harbor-with-the-vcenter-event-broker-appliance/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/veba_harbor_cover.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>The vCenter Event Broker Appliance (VEBA) is still one of my favorite open source projects these days and it is evolving rapidly and continuously through the great work of the two main contributors Michael Gasch and William Lam as well as through the valuable feedback from the community. IÂ´m very proud to be part of the &ldquo;inner circle&rdquo; of folks who meet on a regular basis to discuss everything #VEBA and the keyword here is also feedback.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>A Linux Development Desktop with VMware Horizon - Part I: Horizon</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/a-linux-development-desktop-with-vmware-horizon-part-i-horizon/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 16:34:48 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/a-linux-development-desktop-with-vmware-horizon-part-i-horizon/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/devdesk_part_i_cover.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>The Universal Workbench I often thought about writing down my experiences on the topics of Jumphosts, Shell-modifications and useful tools in a series of blog posts, but I hadnÂ´t found the right moment, until I saw the following Tweet, where Alex asked his followers how they get access to a Linux system if they arenÂ´t running Linux on their workstation (locally).
 Ubuntu 18.04 VDI desktop
&mdash; Mark Brookfield ðŸ‡¬ðŸ‡§ (@virtualhobbit) December 28, 2019   Similar to MarkÂ´s answer, IÂ´m also using a VDI (Virtual-Desktop-Infrastructure) desktop for my purposes and I began writing this series&hellip;back in January&hellip;time passed by and due to other projects I worked on and which demanded a lot of my attention (VEBA ðŸ˜), it took a little bit longer to publish them.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>A Linux Development Desktop with VMware Horizon - Part II: Applications </title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/a-linux-development-desktop-with-vmware-horizon-part-ii-applications/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 16:33:48 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/a-linux-development-desktop-with-vmware-horizon-part-ii-applications/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/devdesk_part_ii_cover.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Applications In this section IÂ´m going to list a couple of applications which IÂ´m using for my desktop and how you can easily install them from your shell. Of course, itÂ´s not a must and itÂ´s up to you which of them youÂ´d like to install.
Google Chrome https://www.google.com/chrome/
Firefox is pre-installed on Ubuntu as well as on CentOS but IÂ´m for years now with Chrome and IÂ´m still satisfied.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
