<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Harbor - Tag - Robert Guske</title>
        <link>https://rguske.github.io/tags/harbor/</link>
        <description>Harbor - Tag - Robert Guske</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>robert.guske@gmail.com (Robert Guske)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>robert.guske@gmail.com (Robert Guske)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License. © All rights reserved -2018</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 22:00:36 &#43;0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rguske.github.io/tags/harbor/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Using Harbor with the vCenter Event Broker Appliance</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/using-harbor-with-the-vcenter-event-broker-appliance/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 22:00:36 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/using-harbor-with-the-vcenter-event-broker-appliance/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/veba_harbor_cover.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>The vCenter Event Broker Appliance (VEBA) is still one of my favorite open source projects these days and it is evolving rapidly and continuously through the great work of the two main contributors Michael Gasch and William Lam as well as through the valuable feedback from the community. I´m very proud to be part of the &ldquo;inner circle&rdquo; of folks who meet on a regular basis to discuss everything #VEBA and the keyword here is also feedback.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>docker run vic-machine</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/docker-run-vic-machine/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 22:52:18 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/docker-run-vic-machine/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/dockerrunvicmachine_cover.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Introduction The deployment of a Virtual Container Host (VCH) can be done in various ways. One easy way is to use the vSphere-Client (H5) plugin which gives you the ability to configure all necessary parameters e.g. for network, storage or deployment target through a step-by-step deployment wizard. The far more efficient variant in my opinion is making use of the vic-machine utility, a Command Line Interface which is part of the vSphere Integrated Containers Engine bundle.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
