<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Horizon - Tag - Robert Guske</title>
        <link>https://rguske.github.io/tags/horizon/</link>
        <description>Horizon - Tag - Robert Guske</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>robert.guske@gmail.com (Robert Guske)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>robert.guske@gmail.com (Robert Guske)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License. Â© All rights reserved -2018</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 16:34:48 &#43;0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rguske.github.io/tags/horizon/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>A Linux Development Desktop with VMware Horizon - Part I: Horizon</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/a-linux-development-desktop-with-vmware-horizon-part-i-horizon/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 16:34:48 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/a-linux-development-desktop-with-vmware-horizon-part-i-horizon/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/devdesk_part_i_cover.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>I often thought about writing down my experiences on the topics of Jumphosts, Shell-modifications and useful tools in a series of blog posts, but I hadnÂ´t found the right moment, until I saw the following Tweet, where Alex asked his followers how they get access to a Linux system if they arenÂ´t running Linux on their workstation (locally).
 Ubuntu 18.04 VDI desktop
&mdash; Mark Brookfield (@virtualhobbit) December 28, 2019   Similar to MarkÂ´s answer, IÂ´m also using a VDI (Virtual-Desktop-Infrastructure) desktop for my purposes and I began writing this series&hellip;back in January&hellip;time passed by and due to other projects I worked on and which demanded a lot of my attention (#VEBA ðŸ˜), it took a little bit longer to publish them.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>A Linux Development Desktop with VMware Horizon - Part II: Applications </title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/a-linux-development-desktop-with-vmware-horizon-part-ii-applications/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 16:33:48 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/a-linux-development-desktop-with-vmware-horizon-part-ii-applications/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/devdesk_part_ii_cover.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Applications In this section IÂ´m going to list a couple of applications which IÂ´m using for my desktop and how you can easily install them from your shell. Of course, itÂ´s not a must and itÂ´s up to you which of them youÂ´d like to install.
Google Chrome https://www.google.com/chrome/
Firefox is pre-installed on Ubuntu as well as on CentOS but IÂ´m for years now with Chrome and IÂ´m still satisfied.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>A Linux Development Desktop with VMware Horizon - Part III: Shell</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/a-linux-development-desktop-with-vmware-horizon-part-iii-shell/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 16:32:48 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/a-linux-development-desktop-with-vmware-horizon-part-iii-shell/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/devdesk_part_iii_cover.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>High âš¡ Way to Shell The operationalization of platforms such as e.g. Kubernetes, or the use of tools for building services or applications such as Docker, requires in both cases the use of the command-line. There are dozens of great plugins, themes and extensions out there to pimp your shell so that itÂ´ll help you to increase velocity as well as useability.
Part III of my series is focused on the Shell and which &ldquo;Highway&rdquo; you can take to have the described tool available at the end.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
