<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Serverless - Category - Blog Robert Guske</title>
        <link>https://rguske.github.io/categories/serverless/</link>
        <description>Serverless - Category - Blog Robert Guske</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>robert.guske@gmail.com (Robert Guske)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>robert.guske@gmail.com (Robert Guske)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License. © All rights reserved -2018</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 21:30:31 &#43;0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rguske.github.io/categories/serverless/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Elevate your Cloud-Native Journey: Knative the VMware Tanzu Way Part I - Streamlined Installation of Knative</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/elevate-your-cloud-native-journey-knative-the-vmware-tanzu-way-part-1-streamlined-installation-of-knative/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 21:30:31 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/elevate-your-cloud-native-journey-knative-the-vmware-tanzu-way-part-1-streamlined-installation-of-knative/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/cnr_knative_cover.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><h2 id="knative-blue_heart">Knative &#x1f499;</h2>
<p>In the rapidly evolving landscape of modern software architecture, event-driven systems have emerged as a pivotal paradigm, empowering organizations to create highly responsive, scalable, and adaptable applications. Knative stands at the forefront of this revolution, offering a robust and flexible framework for building event-driven architectures (EDA) that seamlessly integrate diverse components, enhance automation, and enable real-time data processing.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m evangelizing and supporting the <a href="https://knative.dev/docs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer ">Knative project</a> for a longer time already. I recently had the pleasure to demonstrate parts of its comprehensive feature set at the great <a href="https://www.containerdays.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer ">ContainerDays</a> event in beautiful Hamburg, Germany.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Event-Driven Automation with Project Harbor and Knative</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/event-driven-automation-with-project-harbor-and-knative/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 12:00:54 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/event-driven-automation-with-project-harbor-and-knative/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/harbor-webhook-function-cover.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>The open-source container registry Harbor supports the configuration of webhook endpoints. Harbor notifies the webhook endpoint of certain events that occur in a project. However, the event sent is not delivered as a CloudEvent. By leveraging the power of VEBA/Knative the non-CloudEvent can be send to a webhook function to get transformed in a CloudEvent. By transforming the event, other functions can be subscribed to the new event to ultimately get triggered. As a use case for it, I'm going to describe how ChatOps can be enabled using event-driven automation.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Demoing Knative Serving and Eventing using Demo-Magic-Scripts</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/demoing-knative-serving-and-eventing-using-demo-magic-scripts/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 20:00:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/demoing-knative-serving-and-eventing-using-demo-magic-scripts/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/knative_post_cover.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Knative is the most popular platform to run Serverless workload on Kubernetes and to build event-driven architectures. This posts introduces two demo-scripts which will support you when presenting on Knative's power in the mentioned disciplines.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>VMware Event Broker Appliance - vSphere HA Event Notification Function</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-ha-event-notification-function/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 15:19:05 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-ha-event-notification-function/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/harestartfunction_cover.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>A post about a community function contribution to the open source project VMware Event Broker Appliance to notify you if a ESXi host failure occured.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
