<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on </title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 17:40:38 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rguske.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Event-driven interactions with vSphere using Functions as a Service</title>
      <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/event-driven-interactions-with-vsphere-using-functions-as-a-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 17:40:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/event-driven-interactions-with-vsphere-using-functions-as-a-service/</guid>
      <description>When was the last time that you were so much taken by a topic or better by a combination of several, that just by thinking about it your face is filled with enthusiasm?
For me, it&amp;rsquo;s only been a few days ago and it was in one of these afterwork-calls with my well appreciated colleague and friend Michael Gasch where we talked about things we were working on. I had just published my recent post on &amp;ldquo;Monitoring Container VMs with vRealize Operations Manager&amp;rdquo; were I described how I built a dashboard for &amp;amp; with vRealize Operations Manager to monitor the utilization and performance for two of the major objects from vSphere Integrated Containers, the Virtual Container Host (VCH) and the Container-VMs (cVM).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Container VMs with vRealize Operations Manager</title>
      <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/monitoring-container-vms-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 23:00:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/monitoring-container-vms-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</guid>
      <description>Based on talks with customers who already made their experiences running containerized applications in test as well as in production and who are using vSphere Integrated Containers for their way to go, I decided to build a dashboard to monitor those workloads (Container-VMs) with VMware´s Cloud Management Solution, vRealize Operations Manager (vR Ops).

Figure I: VIC monitoring high level overview
The Dashboard Treating Containers as &amp;ldquo;First-Class Citizens&amp;rdquo; is what vSphere Integrated Containers can offer to IT-(Dev)Ops Teams through instantiating a Container-Image as a Virtual Machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Youtube Hugo-Shortcode workaround - when {{&lt; youtube &gt;}} won´t work</title>
      <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/youtube-hugo-shortcode-workaround-when-youtube-wont-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 17:23:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/youtube-hugo-shortcode-workaround-when-youtube-wont-work/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by a recent post from my friend, (Go)Hugo and Git mentor Michael Gasch 😉, where he describes how he fixed the Hugo Shortcode for Twitter to suppress the default thread view, it came to my mind immediately that I faced a similar issue when I started blogging with the Shortcode which embeds a Youtube-Video into your post.
See how Michael fixed the normal behavior for the Twitter Shortcode {{&amp;lt; tweet &amp;gt;}} here&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade vSphere Integrated Containers</title>
      <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/upgrade-vsphere-integrated-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:11:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/upgrade-vsphere-integrated-containers/</guid>
      <description>I like upgrades! Because mostly they bring cool new features with them or eliminate disturbing issues. In this post I´d like to guide you through the upgrade process of VMware vSphere Integrated Containers  from version v1.3.1 to v1.4.1 which is a major upgrade and also to v1.4.3 which is a minor upgrade.
Thanks Tom Schwaller for reviewing this article.
First of all and this applies to all upgrades, we have to check the compatibility and dependencys with our infrastructure components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere Integrated Containers Part IV: docker run a Container-VM</title>
      <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-integrated-containers-part-iv-docker-run-a-container-vm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 13:31:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-integrated-containers-part-iv-docker-run-a-container-vm/</guid>
      <description>Now that we´ve become more familiar with the Virtual Container Host, it´s time to run our first Container-VM on it. The following example will show you how easy it is to instantiate an Nginx  Web Server container-image.
We first pull down the image from Docker Hub to our Datastore by using docker -H 192.168.100.222:2376 --tls pull vmwarecna/nginx. You´ll see some running tasks in your vCenter taskbar under Recent Tasks. Validate the downloaded image with docker -H 192.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere Integrated Containers Part III: Deployment of a Virtual Container Host</title>
      <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-integrated-containers-part-iii-deployment-of-a-virtual-container-host/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 13:21:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-integrated-containers-part-iii-deployment-of-a-virtual-container-host/</guid>
      <description>In this part I´d like to guide you through the Deployment of a Virtual Container Host aka VCH. I definitely don ́t want to make it a habit to use already written descriptions, but this one described it very well, thus I had like to quote this:
 A VCH is the virtual functional equivalent of a Linux VM running Docker. From a Docker client point of view, the Virtual Container Host looks very similar to a native Docker host.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere Integrated Containers Part II: vSphere Client Plug-In</title>
      <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-integrated-containers-part-ii-vsphere-client-plug-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 13:17:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-integrated-containers-part-ii-vsphere-client-plug-in/</guid>
      <description>In this section, I´d like to give you a walkthrough on how to install the VIC vSphere Client Plug-In for the vCenter Server Appliance. I´m already using the vCenter Server Appliance aka vCSA in Version 6.7.0. In general, it is important to know that a minimum version of vCenter Server 6.5.0d is required to make use of the plug-in.
However! It is also worth to be mentioned that the plug-in is not necessary or a requirement to run VIC as well as for the deployment of a Virtual Container Host aka VCH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere Integrated Containers Part I: OVA Deployment</title>
      <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-integrated-containers-part-i-ova-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 13:10:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-integrated-containers-part-i-ova-deployment/</guid>
      <description>Environment Pre-Requisites:
 vSphere Enterprise Plus license or vSphere Remote Office Branch Office (ROBO) Advanced (!)  Dependency on the vDistributed Switch VIC also supports VMware NSX  User with administrative credentials to vCenter Internet Access for downloading images min. two vDistributed Switch Port Groups  for public communication (VCH to external network) for inter containers communication create a dedicated port group for use as the bridge network for each VCH If DHCP is not available on these segments, please, request a range of free IP-Addresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware vSphere Integrated Containers: Introduction</title>
      <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/vmware-vsphere-integrated-containers-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 13:03:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/vmware-vsphere-integrated-containers-introduction/</guid>
      <description>I´m very keen on everything related to Cloud-Native and all topics around the decoupling of a process from the underlying operating system and as well much more on the infrastructure underneath in order to run those distributed systems, which are the result by the end of the day.
For me personally, it became so present in 2016 for the first time and far more when I decided to work for VMware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sometimes you gotta run before you can walk</title>
      <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/sometimes-you-gotta-run-before-you-can-walk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 09:39:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/sometimes-you-gotta-run-before-you-can-walk/</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip;and the first lines are the main ones when you´re working on your first post. Many, many thoughts had been running through my head before I decided to write a blog…“Where to start?”…“Is it just another blog?”…and the most frightening idea…“What if YOU, the reader, don´t like what I´m writing about?”
So what&amp;hellip;I´d like to handle these thoughts like Tony Stark did it in one of my absolute favorite movies Iron Man (1), where he told J.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>