<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Monitoring - Tag - Robert Guske</title>
        <link>https://rguske.github.io/tags/monitoring/</link>
        <description>Monitoring - Tag - Robert Guske</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>robert.guske@gmail.com (Robert Guske)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>robert.guske@gmail.com (Robert Guske)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License. © All rights reserved -2018</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 23:59:50 &#43;0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rguske.github.io/tags/monitoring/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Monitoring the VMware Event Broker Appliance with vRealize Operations Manager</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/monitoring-the-vmware-event-broker-appliance-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 23:59:50 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/monitoring-the-vmware-event-broker-appliance-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/vrops_veba_cover.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Since the VMware Event Broker Appliance (VEBA) is reaching more and more folks out there and the interest is growing steadily, it is important to validate the integration with other solutions (preferably VMware). At least that&rsquo;s what I thought 😉.
Monitoring in terms of utilization and performance captured my interest. So, how can I monitor not only the appliance (virtual machine) but also the Kubernetes components like the Control Plane (Master), the Node(s) as well as the Pods?]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Monitoring Container VMs with vRealize Operations Manager</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/monitoring-container-vms-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 23:00:09 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/monitoring-container-vms-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/vic_monitoring_cover.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Based on talks with customers who already made their experiences running containerized applications in test as well as in production and who are using vSphere Integrated Containers for their way to go, I decided to build a dashboard to monitor those workloads (Container-VMs) with VMware´s Cloud Management Solution, vRealize Operations Manager (vR Ops).
Figure I: VIC monitoring high level overview" Figure I: VIC monitoring high level overview  The Dashboard Treating Containers as &ldquo;First-Class Citizens&rdquo; is what vSphere Integrated Containers can offer to IT-(Dev)Ops Teams through instantiating a Container-Image as a Virtual Machine.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
