<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - Robert Guske</title>
        <link>https://rguske.github.io/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | Robert Guske</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>robert.guske@gmail.com (Robert Guske)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>robert.guske@gmail.com (Robert Guske)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License. © All rights reserved -2018</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 09:00:58 &#43;0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rguske.github.io/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Rebuilding from the Break - Restoring the VMware Avi Controller</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/rebuilding-from-the-break-restoring-the-vmware-avi-controller/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 09:00:58 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/rebuilding-from-the-break-restoring-the-vmware-avi-controller/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/recover_avi_ctrl_cover.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Avi Portal - Bad Service Oh my! I wasn&rsquo;t expecting a three-part series as an outcome of my recent homelab crash, but here we are 😄 Check out my recent posts Database Resurrection - Reviving vPostgres DB on VMware vCenter Server and Fixing vCenter Postgres Archiver Service - Dead Postgres Replication Slot on my made experiences with recovering the vCenter Server database.
Actually, I thought I was &ldquo;out of the woods&rdquo; with fixiing the broken but unfortunately my Avi Controller was also affected from the outage.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Fixing vCenter Postgres Archiver Service - Dead Postgres Replication Slot</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/fixing-vcenter-postgres-archiver-service-dead-replication-slot/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 16:00:47 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/fixing-vcenter-postgres-archiver-service-dead-replication-slot/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/vcsa_vpostgres_archiver_trouble_cover.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Of course I run Backups 🤥 This time I had luck with the outcome of my recent homelab crash. If I weren&rsquo;t able to fix my broken vCenter Server, as described in my previous article, I would have had to reinstall my vSphere (+ vSAN, + Tanzu) environment basically from scratch again.
Is this actually true?
Actually NO! Because if I would have configured my vSphere environment correctly, vCenter Server file-based backup were configured properly and I wouldn&rsquo;t have had to worry about the consequences in the end.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Database Resurrection - Reviving vPostgres DB on VMware vCenter Server</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/database-resurrection-reviving-postgres-on-vmware-vcenter/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 23:44:08 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/database-resurrection-reviving-postgres-on-vmware-vcenter/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/vcsa_vpostgres_trouble_cover.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Power Failure causes Problems again Once in a while power failures happen and can (mostly will!) cause troubles for small homelabs like mine. I&rsquo;m running a two-node vSAN cluster on two Supermicro SYS-E200-8D servers. My vSAN Witness Appliance is running on a small Intel NUC, which is perfectly suited for this use case. The vCenter Server is still running on the vSAN cluster but only compute-wise. I have a Synology NAS running as well which is providing an additional NFS datastore in order to have at least the VCSA (VM) storage outsourced from the cluster.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Elevate your Cloud-Native Journey: Knative the VMware Tanzu Way Part I - Streamlined Installation of Knative</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/elevate-your-cloud-native-journey-knative-the-vmware-tanzu-way-part-1-streamlined-installation-of-knative/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 21:30:31 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/elevate-your-cloud-native-journey-knative-the-vmware-tanzu-way-part-1-streamlined-installation-of-knative/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/cnr_knative_cover.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Knative 💙 In the rapidly evolving landscape of modern software architecture, event-driven systems have emerged as a pivotal paradigm, empowering organizations to create highly responsive, scalable, and adaptable applications. Knative stands at the forefront of this revolution, offering a robust and flexible framework for building event-driven architectures (EDA) that seamlessly integrate diverse components, enhance automation, and enable real-time data processing.
I&rsquo;m evangelizing and supporting the Knative project for a longer time already.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>vSphere with Tanzu Supervisor Services Part IV - Virtual Machine Service to support Hybrid Application Architectures</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-with-tanzu-supervisor-services-part-iv-virtual-machine-service-to-support-hybrid-application-architectures/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 19:48:14 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-with-tanzu-supervisor-services-part-iv-virtual-machine-service-to-support-hybrid-application-architectures/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/ova-vm-service-cover.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Hybrid Application Architectures As technology advances at a rapid pace, the landscape of application development continues to evolve. The demand for agility, scalability, and cost-effectiveness has given rise to a new breed of architectures that seamlessly integrate modern cloud-native principles with established traditional workloads. One such paradigm that has gained significant traction is the hybrid application architecture, which combines the power of service-oriented architectures (SOA) with the reliability and versatility of virtual machines (VMs).]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>vSphere with Tanzu Supervisor Services Part III - Lifecycle Management of Supervisor Services</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-with-tanzu-supervisor-services-part-iii-lifecycle-management-of-supervisor-services/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 11:50:04 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-with-tanzu-supervisor-services-part-iii-lifecycle-management-of-supervisor-services/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/supervisor-services-3-cover.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Recap and Intro In Part I and II of my blog series on the Supervisor Services in vSphere with Tanzu (TKG with Supervisor Model), I covered the topics from registering and installing a new service on a Supervisor Cluster until how to leverage a service for functionalities like e.g. hosting container images (Registry Service) or handling incoming traffic (Ingress Service) for vSphere Pod based applications.
Through this part, I&rsquo;d like to bring you the lifecycle of a Supervisor Service a bit closer.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>vSphere with Tanzu Supervisor Services Part II - Ingress with Contour for vSphere Pod based Applications</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-with-tanzu-supervisor-services-part-ii-ingress-with-contour-for-vsphere-pod-based-applications/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 11:30:30 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-with-tanzu-supervisor-services-part-ii-ingress-with-contour-for-vsphere-pod-based-applications/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/supervisor-services-2-cover.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Recap and Intro In Part I of my blog series on the Supervisor Services in vSphere with Tanzu (TKGS), I introduced the overall concept, the idea, the requirements as well as how to register and install a new Supervisor Service in vSphere.
Read HERE
Furthermore, I covered the feature vSphere Pods and how they come to beneficial use for the Supervisor Services.
Read HERE
In this second part, I&rsquo;m going to demonstrate how the Kubernetes Ingress Controller Service (Contour) will be used for serving a vSphere Pod based web-shop application with Ingress functionalities.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>vSphere with Tanzu Supervisor Services Part I - Introduction and How-To</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-with-tanzu-supervisor-services-part-i-introduction-and-how-to/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 16:30:46 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-with-tanzu-supervisor-services-part-i-introduction-and-how-to/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/supervisor-services-1-cover.jpeg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>To begin with, if you are familiar with vSphere Pods in general, you can skip the first chapter of this post and directly go to the chapter Supervisor Services.
Recap - Embed Containers and Kubernetes into vSphere When VMware released vSphere 7 back in 2020, it was announced that under the hood a lot of architectural efforts flowed into VMware&rsquo;s core platform. These efforts had to be done in order to embed containers and Kubernetes into vSphere, to unify them with virtual machines as first class citizens.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Using Windows SMB Shares in Kubernetes</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/using-windows-smb-shares-in-kubernetes/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 11:21:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/using-windows-smb-shares-in-kubernetes/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/csi-smb-cover.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Using Windows Fileserver shares in Kubernetes? This post introduce how this can be achieved by installing and using the SMB CSI driver for Kubernetes.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Event-Driven Automation with Project Harbor and Knative</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/event-driven-automation-with-project-harbor-and-knative/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 12:00:54 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/event-driven-automation-with-project-harbor-and-knative/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/harbor-webhook-function-cover.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>The open-source container registry Harbor supports the configuration of webhook endpoints. Harbor notifies the webhook endpoint of certain events that occur in a project. However, the event sent is not delivered as a CloudEvent. By leveraging the power of VEBA/Knative the non-CloudEvent can be send to a webhook function to get transformed in a CloudEvent. By transforming the event, other functions can be subscribed to the new event to ultimately get triggered. As a use case for it, I'm going to describe how ChatOps can be enabled using event-driven automation.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
