<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - Robert Guske</title>
        <link>https://rguske.github.io/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | Robert Guske</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>robert.guske@gmail.com (Robert Guske)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>robert.guske@gmail.com (Robert Guske)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License. © All rights reserved -2018</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 11:30:30 &#43;0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rguske.github.io/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>vSphere with Tanzu Supervisor Services Part II - Ingress with Contour for vSphere Pod based Applications</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-with-tanzu-supervisor-services-part-ii-ingress-with-contour-for-vsphere-pod-based-applications/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 11:30:30 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-with-tanzu-supervisor-services-part-ii-ingress-with-contour-for-vsphere-pod-based-applications/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/supervisor-services-2-cover.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Recap and Intro In Part I of my blog series on the Supervisor Services in vSphere with Tanzu (TKGS), I introdcued the overall concept, the idea, the requirements as well as how to register and install a new Supervisor Service in vSphere.
Read HERE
Furthermore, I covered the feature vSphere Pods and how they come to beneficial use for the Supervisor Services.
Read HERE
In this second part, I&rsquo;m going to demonstrate how the Kubernetes Ingress Controller Service (Contour) will be used for serving a vSphere Pod based web-shop application with Ingress functionalities.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>vSphere with Tanzu Supervisor Services Part I - Introduction and How-To</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-with-tanzu-supervisor-services-part-i-introduction-and-how-to/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 16:30:46 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/vsphere-with-tanzu-supervisor-services-part-i-introduction-and-how-to/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/supervisor-services-1-cover.jpeg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>To begin with, if you are familiar with vSphere Pods in general, you can skip the first chapter of this post and directly go to the chapter Supervisor Services.
Recap - Embed Containers and Kubernetes into vSphere When VMware released vSphere 7 back in 2020, it was announced that under the hood a lot of architectural efforts flowed into VMware&rsquo;s core platform. These efforts had to be done in order to embed containers and Kubernetes into vSphere, to unify them with virtual machines as first class citizens.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Using Windows SMB Shares in Kubernetes</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/using-windows-smb-shares-in-kubernetes/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 11:21:00 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/using-windows-smb-shares-in-kubernetes/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/csi-smb-cover.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Using Windows Fileserver shares in Kubernetes? This post introduce how this can be achieved by installing and using the SMB CSI driver for Kubernetes.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Event-Driven Automation with Project Harbor and Knative</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/event-driven-automation-with-project-harbor-and-knative/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 12:00:54 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/event-driven-automation-with-project-harbor-and-knative/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/harbor-webhook-function-cover.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>The open-source container registry Harbor supports the configuration of webhook endpoints. Harbor notifies the webhook endpoint of certain events that occur in a project. However, the event sent is not delivered as a CloudEvent. By leveraging the power of VEBA/Knative the non-CloudEvent can be send to a webhook function to get transformed in a CloudEvent. By transforming the event, other functions can be subscribed to the new event to ultimately get triggered. As a use case for it, I'm going to describe how ChatOps can be enabled using event-driven automation.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Demoing Knative Serving and Eventing using Demo-Magic-Scripts</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/demoing-knative-serving-and-eventing-using-demo-magic-scripts/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 20:00:11 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/demoing-knative-serving-and-eventing-using-demo-magic-scripts/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/knative_post_cover.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Knative is the most popular platform to run Serverless workload on Kubernetes and to build event-driven architectures. This posts introduces two demo-scripts which will support you when presenting on Knative's power in the mentioned disciplines.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Sharing Container Images using the Docker CLI or Carvel&#39;s imgpkg</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/sharing-container-images-using-the-docker-cli-or-carvels-imgpkg/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 16:20:24 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/sharing-container-images-using-the-docker-cli-or-carvels-imgpkg/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/sharing-container-images-cover.jpeg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Learn how to make container images available in a shareable format, to support e.g. air-gapped deployments, using the Docker CLI or imgpkg by Carvel.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Building a VMware PhotonOS based Kubernetes Appliance for vSphere</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/building-a-vmware-photonos-based-kubernetes-appliance/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 14:19:55 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/building-a-vmware-photonos-based-kubernetes-appliance/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/kubernetes_appliance_cover.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Why a Kubernetes-Appliance? Learning Kubernetes (K8s) is still in great demand and is by no means decreasing. Starting with the theory is essential but we all know, the fun part starts with pactice. Quickly instantiating a Kubernetes cluster is made easy and I&rsquo;m pretty sure it won&rsquo;t take long until KinD crosses your path. But sometimes, a local K8s instance isn&rsquo;t enough and practicing Kubernetes low-level implementations like e.g. for networking (CNI) or storage (CSI) on real cloud environments is crucial.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Deploy VMware Tanzu Packages from a private Container Registry</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/deploy-tanzu-packages-from-a-private-registry/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 12:00:40 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/deploy-tanzu-packages-from-a-private-registry/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/tanzu_packages_offline_cover.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Offline Requirements During a recent Tanzu engagement, my customer wanted to make use of the VMware Tanzu Packages to extend the core functionalities of their existing Kubernetes clusters. As a requirement, an offline deployment of the Packages was raised, which in other words means, deployments from their own private container registry. The intention behind it is simple.
All of the Tanzu Packages shown in Table I below are provided by VMware.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Deploying Tanzu Packages using Tanzu Mission Control Catalog</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/deploying-tanzu-packages-using-tanzu-mission-control-catalog/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 20:00:27 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/deploying-tanzu-packages-using-tanzu-mission-control-catalog/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/tmc_catalog_202201_cover.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>The Challenge Just providing a Kubernetes cluster to an application team is in most cases half of the battle. It&rsquo;s often necessary to provide certain capabilities for e.g. logging or for ingress to those clusters, to ultimately support a production workload. Extending Kubernetes environments with open source solutions, to support the aforementioned capabilities, should provide a decent level of simplicity in terms of deployment and lifecycle management.
A Catalog of Extensions Tanzu Mission Control, a VMware Cloud Service (SaaS), is VMware&rsquo;s multi-cloud Kubernetes management platform which provides a centralized management for consistently operating and securing Kubernetes infrastructures and modern applications through a centralized policy management across all deployed and attached Kubernetes clusters.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Hands-on the Avi Kubernetes Operator (AKO)</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/hands-on-the-avi-kubernetes-operator-nsx-advanced-loadbalancer/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 11:00:59 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Robert Guske</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/hands-on-the-avi-kubernetes-operator-nsx-advanced-loadbalancer/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/handsonako_cover.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>A hands on guide which covers the deployment and configuration of the Avi Kubernetes Operator and to ultimately integrate it with the NSX Advanced Load Balancer to make use of the modern and comprehensive features of VMware's Next Gen Load Balancer.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
