<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>February2020 on </title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/tags/february2020/</link>
    <description>Recent content in February2020 on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 16:34:48 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rguske.github.io/tags/february2020/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Linux Development Desktop with VMware Horizon - Part I: Horizon</title>
      <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/a-linux-development-desktop-with-vmware-horizon-part-i-horizon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 16:34:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/a-linux-development-desktop-with-vmware-horizon-part-i-horizon/</guid>
      <description>I often thought about writing down my experiences on the topics of Jumphosts, Shell-modifications and useful tools in a series of blog posts, but I hadn´t found the right moment, until I saw the following Tweet, where Alex asked his followers how they get access to a Linux system if they aren´t running Linux on their workstation (locally).
 Ubuntu 18.04 VDI desktop
&amp;mdash; Mark Brookfield (@virtualhobbit) December 28, 2019</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Linux Development Desktop with VMware Horizon - Part II: Applications </title>
      <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/a-linux-development-desktop-with-vmware-horizon-part-ii-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 16:33:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/a-linux-development-desktop-with-vmware-horizon-part-ii-applications/</guid>
      <description>Previous articles:
 A Linux Development Desktop with VMware Horizon - Part I: Horizon  Applications In this section I´m going to list a couple of applications which I´m using for my desktop and how you can easily install them from your shell. Of course, it´s not a must and it´s up to you which of them you´d like to install.
Google Chrome - https://www.google.com/chrome/ Firefox is pre-installed on Ubuntu as well as on CentOS but I´m for years now with Chrome and I´m still satisfied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Linux Development Desktop with VMware Horizon - Part III: Shell</title>
      <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/a-linux-development-desktop-with-vmware-horizon-part-iii-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 16:32:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/a-linux-development-desktop-with-vmware-horizon-part-iii-shell/</guid>
      <description>Previous articles:
 A Linux Development Desktop with VMware Horizon - Part I: Horizon A Linux Development Desktop with VMware Horizon - Part II: Applications  High ⚡️ Way to Shell The operationalization of platforms such as Kubernetes, or the use of tools for building services or applications such as Docker, requires in both cases the use of the command-line. There are dozens of great plugins, themes and extensions out there to pimp your shell so that it´ll help you to increase velocity as well as useability.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>