<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>FaaS - Category - Robert Guske</title>
        <link>https://rguske.github.io/categories/faas/</link>
        <description>FaaS - Category - Robert Guske</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>robert.guske@gmail.com (Robert Guske)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>robert.guske@gmail.com (Robert Guske)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License. © All rights reserved -2018</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 23:59:50 &#43;0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rguske.github.io/categories/faas/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Monitoring the VMware Event Broker Appliance with vRealize Operations Manager</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/monitoring-the-vmware-event-broker-appliance-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 23:59:50 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/monitoring-the-vmware-event-broker-appliance-with-vrealize-operations-manager/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/vrops_veba_cover.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Since the VMware Event Broker Appliance (VEBA) is reaching more and more folks out there and the interest is growing steadily, it is important to validate the integration with other solutions (preferably VMware). At least that&rsquo;s what I thought 😉.
Monitoring in terms of utilization and performance captured my interest. So, how can I monitor not only the appliance (virtual machine) but also the Kubernetes components like the Control Plane (Master), the Node(s) as well as the Pods?]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Using Harbor with the vCenter Event Broker Appliance</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/using-harbor-with-the-vcenter-event-broker-appliance/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 22:00:36 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/using-harbor-with-the-vcenter-event-broker-appliance/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/veba_harbor_cover.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>The vCenter Event Broker Appliance (VEBA) is still one of my favorite open source projects these days and it is evolving rapidly and continuously through the great work of the two main contributors Michael Gasch and William Lam as well as through the valuable feedback from the community. I´m very proud to be part of the &ldquo;inner circle&rdquo; of folks who meet on a regular basis to discuss everything #VEBA and the keyword here is also feedback.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Event-driven interactions with vSphere using Functions as a Service</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/event-driven-interactions-with-vsphere-using-functions-as-a-service/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 17:40:38 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/event-driven-interactions-with-vsphere-using-functions-as-a-service/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/vspheretagfn_cover.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Note  I am very happy to inform you that the below described idea has become a VMware Fling (completely OpenSource).
Official website of VMware Event Broker Appliance: https://vmweventbroker.io/
   When was the last time that you were so much taken by a topic or better by a combination of several, that just by thinking about it your face is filled with enthusiasm?
For me, it&rsquo;s only been a few days ago and it was in one of these afterwork-calls with my well appreciated colleague and friend Michael Gasch where we talked about things we were working on.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
