<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Fusion - Category - Robert Guske</title>
        <link>https://rguske.github.io/categories/fusion/</link>
        <description>Fusion - Category - Robert Guske</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>robert.guske@gmail.com (Robert Guske)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>robert.guske@gmail.com (Robert Guske)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License. © All rights reserved -2018</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 12:00:57 &#43;0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rguske.github.io/categories/fusion/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>A practitioner&#39;s guide - Spin up a local VEBA environment with KinD and vCenter simulator</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/spin-up-a-local-veba-environment-with-kind-and-vcenter-simulator/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 12:00:57 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/spin-up-a-local-veba-environment-with-kind-and-vcenter-simulator/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/vebakindvcsim_cover.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Introduction In my previous blog post I took A closer look at VMware&rsquo;s Project Nautilus and went through some of the implementation details (Fusion 12). I described how it provides a single development platform on the desktop by enabling you to run, build and manage OCI compliant Containers as well as how easy it is now to instantiate Kubernetes Clusters besides Virtual Machines.
The question This post is intented to answer a question which came into my mind during my work on VMware&rsquo;s Open Source project VMware Event Broker Appliance (VEBA) and as I&rsquo;ve heard of Project Nautilus for the first time.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>A closer look at VMware&#39;s Project Nautilus</title>
    <link>https://rguske.github.io/post/a-closer-look-at-vmwares-project-nautilus/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 11:45:57 &#43;0200</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://rguske.github.io/post/a-closer-look-at-vmwares-project-nautilus/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/img/projectnautilus_cover.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>General Availability Fusion 12 &amp; Workstation 16 VMware&rsquo;s Desktop Hypervisor solutions Fusion for Mac users and Workstation for the Windows and Linux userbase were launched in it&rsquo;s newest versions on September 15th. Lots of new features, enhancements and support around VM Guest Operating Systems, VM Scaling, GPU, Containers and Kubernetes has made it into these releases. The made enhancements will enrich Developers tool kit as well as will provide great new capabilities for IT Admins and everyone else who is keen on spinning up and down Virtual Machines, Containers and NOW also Kubernetes.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
